ALEX WEN

alexwen.me

4 630-935-5262

A web developer committed to solving tomorrow's problems by learning from yesterday's lessons, I am driven by my technical knowledge and creative passion to create meaningful and progressive change to the world.

Skills

lonic + AngularJS Ruby on Rails Javascript HTML + CSS

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe InDesign

Autodesk Inventor

AutoCAD

SQL

Pro/Engineer

Microsoft Office

Projects

Murakami

Developed a digital book club mobile application that allowed users to interact with each other, track reading progress, and share favorite books. Acted as team lead--from conception of idea to delegation of tasks, developed front-end on lonic and AngularJS, worked on back-end Ruby on Rails.

Sample

Developed a music playing application using Spotify API. Assisted with design, structure, and implementation. Built on Ruby on Rails, Javascript and HTML.

Daqri Augmented Reality Smart Helmet Design Analysis

Worked with Daqri on the Smart Helmet prototype--winner of the 2015 Edison Gold Award for Industrial Solutions. Offered design suggestions, provided finite element analysis, and constructed a report on market feasibility.

My Banana Story

Creator of photo campaign to raise awareness on Asian American social justice issues: internalized racism, microaggressions and the model minority myth. Featured on USA Today, Buzz Magazine and Audrey Magazine.

Experiences

Empire Taste

Oct 2013 to Current

Editor-in-Chief, Event Photographer, Front-End Developer

Interview and plan marketing strategies with emerging artists. Photograph concerts and festivals. Editing and writing features on hip-hop artists and culture. Design and create websites for brands and artists.

Sigmatron International

Jun 2015 to Apr 2016

Sourcing Analyst

Established relationships with vendors and manufacturers to quote electronic components and assemblies. Assisted in successful negotiation of multi-million dollar appliance business opportunity. Collaborated with program mangers to win multiple business contracts valued at over \$500K each.

Asian American Writers' Workshop

Jan 2015 to Jun 2015

Editorial Intern

Managed social media channels with thousands of followers. Editing, copyediting, proofing and fact-checking of articles. Event planning and hosting: photographed author events, sold books, and set-up A/V equipment. Maintained relations with affiliates and donors, including Pultizer Prize-winner Junot Diaz.

Illini Media Jun 2014 to Dec 2014

Page Transmission

Collaborated with The Daily Illini editorial staff to compile pages and send them off for publishing. Technical experience with Indesign and Adobe Illustrator.

Asian Pacific American Coalition

May 2013 to Apr 2014

Co-Director

Facilitated relations as an umbrella organization for 23 affiliated Asian/Asian American organizations. Organized and planned campus-wide events for 1000+ attendees. Networked with university faculty, staff and resources on large-scale events, worked as board member of funding committee.

Education

Dev Bootcamp

Full-stack Development Track 2016

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

BS General Engineering with Secondary Field in Engineering Administration 2014

Awards

College of Engineering · Herbert J. Sprengel Award

May 2015

Awarded by the Industrial and Enterprise Systems Engineering Department for best balsa wood design.

Asian American Cultural Center · Outstanding AA Undergraduate Leader Award

May 2014

Awarded by the Asian American Cultural Center for commitment to the Asian American community at UIUC.